A Guide to the Norfolk Public School Papers, 1922-2006
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
A Guide to the Norfolk Public Schools Desegregation Papers 1922-2006
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
MG 92;
34 Hollinger document cases; 2 oversized Hollinger boxes
Norfolk Public Schools (Norfolk, Va.)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Open to researchers without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was donated by Norfolk, Virginia, Public Schools.
Historical Sketch
Norfolk, Virginia has twice found itself at the center of a storm of attention related to the racial desegregation of its schools. The first was in the late 1950s during a state-wide, governor-led resistance to the integration mandated by the Brown v. Board of Education of Topeka, KS ruling. Governor Lindsay J. Almond, Jr. closed the schools scheduled to be integrated for five months until the courts intervened. The second was in 1986 when Norfolk became the first school district in the country to have a federal judicial ruling allowing them to end busing for the purpose of achieving racial balance in schools.
On September 19, 1958, U.S. District Judge Walter Hoffman issued an order in continuation of Leola Pearl Beckett v. The School Board of the City of Norfolk which said that Norfolk must immediately begin to integrate its schools. On September 27, 1958, the Norfolk School Board placed 17 African American children into previously all white schools in compliance with the judge's order. Earlier in 1958, the Virginia legislature had granted permission to Governor J. Lindsay Almond, Jr. to close any white school that had "negroes" which tried to enroll. On September 27, the same day the children were to start at school, the Governor closed the six affected schools in Norfolk and took them under his control. In all, this impacted more than 10,000 white students and the 17 African American students (the Norfolk 17). In the months that followed, students found avenues to education through private schools, relocation, but mostly through highly organized tutoring groups. In February of 1959, the schools reopened with fewer students-by one estimate almost 2500 fewer.
During the 1960s and 1970s, southern school districts struggled to implement the court-ordered integration in the face of political and community opposition. Districts faced internal challenges of teachers and administrators who did not want to work with students of another race and in many cases had to force involuntary transfers to maintain court-ordered quotas. As African American students began to apply for transfers to predominantly white schools in Norfolk, the district developed a rigorous evaluation system including an examination of records, health requirements, the academic achievement of the student in comparison to the requested school, residence, physical and moral fitness, mental ability (IQ), social adaptability, and cultural background compared to the requested school. The apparent goal and result of these stringent requirements was to give the appearance of compliance, while maintaining the status quo. As the courts and groups such as the NAACP became frustrated with the road blocks to integration, additional court cases were filed and more court orders were disseminated. As the 1960s closed, Norfolk still had not achieved integration and stronger measures needed to be implemented.
The mandatory busing between paired schools in Norfolk, VA began in September of 1971. Within the first weeks of busing, enrollment in the district dropped by 5000 students-within the next two years, an additional 8000 students left the district-mostly white. Four years later, in February of 1975, Judge Mackenzie deemed Norfolk a unitary school district-which meant that it was no longer segregated. As the enrollment of white students continued to drop-termed "white flight"-the School Board became concerned that despite busing, an integrated school district would be impossible to achieve. It examined a multitude of other districts around the country to gain ideas into how best to deal with the challenges. The school board voted in 1983 to end cross-town busing of elementary students, but to continue it for middle and high school. Although they were challenged in the Riddick v. School Board of the City of Norfolk case, their decision was upheld in 1986 when the U.S. Supreme Court refused to review the lower court decision. In the years that followed, a Community Oversight Committee was established to oversee the equity among schools and resources, but disbanded itself in 1991.
Scope and Content
This collection dating from 1922-2006, contains correspondence, memorandum, depositions, court orders, recollections, statistical testing data, printed material, artifacts, and maps. The bulk of the collection provides a glimpse into the decisions made by the School Board through court documentation and the public sentiment during the integration process in Norfolk. The content is arranged chronologically. As such, it is possible that certain topics and materials regarding specific parties may cross series.
Series Descriptions
Series I - Closing of the Norfolk City Schools, 1954-1960 This series contains documents related to the years immediately following the Brown decision through the closing of some of Norfolk's schools. Of special note is the letter from Governor Almond closing the school and materials about the tutoring groups around Norfolk. There are also letters included which may help the researcher understand the climate of the community both in Norfolk and elsewhere during this time. The letters include a letter from an attorney in Seattle who referred to the School Board as "mongrelizers."
Series II - The Path to a Unitary School District, 1960-1983 This series contains a multitude of information regarding Norfolk schools during the 1960s and 1970s. It includes court required reports, internal memorandum, court documents including depositions, and test scores. There are studies and statistics maintained regarding the representation of African Americans both in the staffs of schools and in administrative positions. The city was required to present data regarding both enrollment and test scores by race. Additionally, there was significant community involvement through both litigation and public efforts to push each person's own agenda. Requests by teachers not to be moved to schools predominantly composed of another race are also included. Finally, there is information regarding the tuition grant program and its implementation.
Series III - Norfolk as a Unitary School District and the End of Busing, 1976-1991 This series contains information regarding the era after busing ended in Norfolk. A major component of this series includes the papers of Attorney Jack Greer, school board attorney as well as the plans for rezoning into neighborhood schools. Additionally, the Community Oversight Committee reports are included which provide information regarding equity of facilities and resources following the elimination of cross-town busing.
Series IV - Directories and Calendars, 1922-2006 This series contains calendars and directories for Norfolk schools to include years from 1922-1993. Not all years are included. The directories and calendars provide a mechanism for examining the way in which language changed over time. Beginning in the early years when calendar events were segregated and referred to by black school vs. white school to the time when the calendars became integrated. This also lists all major officials in the school board and administration during the years included.
Series V - Oversized Documents, 1960 - 1984 The final series includes oversized documents. Of special interest are maps of the school zoning in Norfolk and computer printouts of test scores by school broken down by race.
Index Terms
Norfolk Public Schools (Norfolk, Va.); School integration--Virginia--Norfolk; Busing for school integration--Virginia--Norfolk; Correspondence; Memorandums; Depositions; Judicial records; Artifacts; Maps
Contents List
- Closing of the Norfolk City Schools 1954-1960
  - Letters 1954, 1955, 1958 (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Norfolk City Council & School Board 1955-1958 (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Integration-Misc. State Board of Education 1955-1959 (Folder 1:3)
  - Integration-Misc. Statement of School Board 7/1/55 1955 (Folder 1:4)
  - Integration-Misc. Negro Children in White Areas 1955 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Integration-Misc. Defenders 1955-1956 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Integration-Misc. Gray Commission 1955-1956 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Integration 1956 (Box-folder 1:8)
  - Williams, Cocke, Worrell, Kelly (Legal Counsel to Norfolk Schools) 1956-1958 (Box-folder 1:9)
  - NAACP Suit 1956-1958 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Integration Ashe, Madison, Jordan (Negro Attorneys) 1956-1958 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Briefs, Beckett Case 1957 (Box-folder 1:12)
  - Doctrine of Interposition--Its History & Application 1957 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Operating Costs 1958 (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Integration-Misc. Interviewing Committee 1958 (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Integration Q & A 1958 (Box-folder 1:16)
  - Letters 1958 (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Correspondence of City Attorneys Office 1958 (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Integration-1958-1959, Testing Program 1958 (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Salary Reimbursement 1958 (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Tuition Grants 1958-1960 (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Letters from Governor Almond Closing Schools September 1958 (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Integration-Misc. Governor of Virginia 1958 (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Integration 1958-1959, Statement by Crenshaw 15 July 1958 (Box-folder 2:7)
  - Integration 1958-1959, Tutoring Groups 1958-1959 (Box-folder 2:8)
  - Integration 1958-1959, Requests for Placements of 89 Tested 1958-1959 (Box-folder 2:9)
  - Integration 1958-1959, Federal Court 1958-1959 (Box-folder 2:10)
  - School Board Operations and Correspondence, 1958-1959 1958-1959 (Box-folder 2:11)
  - Integration 1958-1959 Resolutions Adopted by School Board 1958-1959 (Box-folder 2:12)
  - Integration 1959-1960 Applications 1959-1960 (Box-folder 2:13)
- The Path to a Unitary School District 1960-1983
  - News Clippings 1960s and 1970s (Box-folder 3:1)
  - Court Orders 1960s (Box-folder 3:2)
  - School Enrollment & Racial Distribution 1960-1972 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - Recommended Assignment of Pupils 1960-1961 (Box-folder 3:4)
  - Integration-Misc. Social Activities 1959-1963 (Box-folder 3:5)
  - Integration-Misc. Requests to Withdraw from White Schools 1960 and 1963 (Box-folder 3:6)
  - Integration 1960-1961 Federal Court 1960-1961 (Box-folder 3:7)
  - Integration 1960-1961 Resolutions Adopted by School Board 1960-1961 (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Integration 1960-1961 Testing Program 1960 (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Integration-Misc. Ashe, Madison, Jordan, Negro Attorneys 1961-1968 (Box-folder 3:10)
  - Integration-Misc. Distances from Applicants Residence to Schools 1961 (Box-folder 3:11)
  - Integration 1961-1962 Resolutions Adopted by School Board 1961-1962 (Box-folder 3:12)
  - Integration 1961-1962 Testing Program 1961 (Box-folder 3:13)
  - Integration 1961-1962, Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box-folder 3:14)
  - Integration 1962-1963 Letters to Parents 1962-1963 (Box-folder 3:15)
  - Integration 1962-1963 Report on 62-63 School Year 1962-1963 (Box-folder 3:16)
  - Integration 1962-1963 Resolutions Adopted by School Board 1962-1963 (Box-folder 3:17)
  - Integration 1962-1963 Probation Students 1962-1963 (Box-folder 3:18)
  - Negro Application 1962-1963 (Box-folder 3:19)
  - Integration 1963-1964, Depositions 1963 1963-1964 (Box-folder 4:1)
  - Integration-Interrogatories 1963 (Box-folder 4:2)
  - Integration 1963-1964 Resolutions Adopted by School Board 1963-1964 (Box-folder 4:3)
  - Integration-Other Cities 1963-1965 (Box-folder 4:4)
  - Choice of Schools 1964 and 1969 (Box-folder 4:5)
  - Integration 1964-1965 Resolutions 1964-1965 (Box-folder 4:6)
  - Principles for Determining 1963 (Box-folder 4:7)
  - Integration 1964-1965 1964 (Box-folder 5:1)
  - Integration 1964-1965 Brief for Defendants 1964 (Box-folder 5:2)
  - City Attorney Tuition Grant Suit, 1964-1965 1964 (Box-folder 5:3)
  - Integration 1964-1965 City Attorney 1964 (Box-folder 5:4)
  - Integration 1964-1965 Federal Court Memorandum & Order 1964 (Box-folder 5:5)
  - Integration 1964-1965 Publication of Plan of School Bd. For Desegregation 1964 (Box-folder 5:6)
  - Enrollment Data Summary 1965 (Box-folder 5:7)
  - Integration 1965-1966, Publication of Plan of School Bd. For Desegregation 1965 (Box-folder 5:8)
  - Integration 1965-1966 City Attorney 1965 (Box-folder 5:9)
  - Tuition Grants 1966 (Box-folder 5:10)
  - Tuition Grants-Douglas MacArthur Acad. (Tidewater Ed. Foundation) 1965-1966 (Box-folder 5:11)
  - Tuition Grants-McLea Day School 1965-1966 (Box-folder 5:12)
  - Tuition Grants-Meadows Private School 1965-1966 (Box-folder 5:13)
  - Tuition Grants-Norfolk Academy 1965-1966 (Box-folder 5:14)
  - Tuition Grants-North Shore Private School 1965-1966 (Box-folder 5:15)
  - Tuition Grants-Mary C. Rice Private School 1965-1966 (Box-folder 5:16)
  - Tuition Grants-Ryan Private School 1965-1966 (Box-folder 5:17)
  - Tuition Grants-Tidewater Association for Retarded Children 1965-1966 (Box-folder 5:18)
  - Tuition Grants-Town & Country Day School 1965-1966 (Box-folder 5:19)
  - Tuition Grants-Twin Oaks Private School 1965-1966 (Box-folder 5:20)
  - Tuition Grants-Wayside Academy 1965-1966 (Box-folder 6:1)
  - Tuition Grants-Arrowood Academy 1965-1966 (Box-folder 6:2)
  - Tuition Grants-Brentwood Day School 1965-1966 (Box-folder 6:3)
  - Tuition Grants-Carolton Oaks School 1965-1966 (Box-folder 6:4)
  - Tuition Grants-Denby Park School 1965-1966 (Box-folder 6:5)
  - Tuition Grants-Garrison Williams School 1965-1966 (Box-folder 6:6)
  - Tuition Grants-Barbara Jacobs School 1965-1966 (Box-folder 6:7)
  - Tuition Grants-Kings Grant Christian Day School 1965-1966 (Box-folder 6:8)
  - Integration 1965-1966 Interrogatories 1965-1966 (Box-folder 6:9)
  - Integration 1965-1966 Resolutions 1965-1966 (Box-folder 6:10)
  - Integration 1965-1966 Resolutions 1965-1966 (Box-folder 6:10)
  - Desegregation of Facilities-Reassignment of Volunteers, Part 1 1966-1970 (Box-folder 6:11)
  - Desegregation of Facilities-Reassignment of Volunteers, Part 2 1966-1970 (Box-folder 6:12)
  - Integration 1966-1967, Response of School Board to Order of the Court 1965 (Box-folder 6:13)
  - Integration, 1966-1967 Statement via TV by Lamberth & Thomas 1966 (Box-folder 6:14)
  - Integration 1966-1967 Teachers 1966 (Box-folder 6:15)
  - Integration-Misc. Wetter, Dr. Allen 1967 (Box-folder 6:16)
  - Percent of White & Black Pupils 1966-1970 (Box-folder 6:17)
  - Distribution of Pupils & Administration by Race 1965, 1970, 1975 (Box-folder 6:18)
  - Integration 1966-1967 Publication of Plan of School Board for Desegregation 1966-1967 (Box-folder 7:1)
  - Integration 1966-1967 Plan of School Board for Desegregation of Schools 1966 (Box-folder 1966)
  - Integration 1966-1967 Resolutions 1966-1967 (Box-folder 7:3)
  - Integration 1966-1967 Choice of School 1966 (Box-folder 7:4)
  - Plan of the School Board, Amended & Modified 23 May 1967 (Box-folder 7:5)
  - Integration 1967-1968 Transfer Requests 1967-1968 (Box-folder 7:6)
  - Integration 1967-1968 Resolutions 1967-1968 (Box-folder 7:7)
  - Special Report on Enrollment as of October 1, 1968 1968 (Box-folder 7:8)
  - Neighborhood Analysis August 1967 (Box-folder 7:9)
  - Integration 1967-1968 Federal Report 1967-1968 (Box-folder 7:10)
  - Integration 1967-1968 City Attorney 1967-1968 (Box-folder 7:11)
  - Integration 1967-1968 Choice of School 1967-1968 (Box-folder 7:12)
  - Submission of Plaintiff-Intervener Pursuant to the Courts Order 1968 (Box-folder 7:13)
  - Compulsory Attendance Law 9 September 1968 (Box-folder 7:14)
  - Integration City Attorney 1966-1967 (Box-folder 8:1)
  - Briefs, Brewer et al 1967 (Box-folder 8:2)
  - Cost Per Pupil by Schools 1968-1969 (Box-folder 8:3)
  - Integration City Attorney 1968-1969 (Box-folder 8:4)
  - Brief Brewer Case 1968 (Box-folder 8:5)
  - Expenditures 12 June 1968 (Box-folder 8:6)
  - Racial Imbalance 1968 October (Box-folder 8:7)
  - Transportation 1968-1977 (Box-folder 8:8)
  - Integration-Federal Court Order Memorandum & Order 1968 (Box-folder 9:1)
  - Estimated Requirements for Transportation of Pupils 1968-1969 (Box-folder 9:2)
  - Integration Resolutions 1968-1969 (Box-folder 9:3)
  - Integration Attorney General 1968-1969 (Box-folder 9:4)
  - Court Orders 1968-1969 (Box-folder 9:5)
  - Integration Requests for Information 1969 (Box-folder 9:6)
  - Norfolk Desegregation 1969 (Box-folder 9:7)
  - Petition for Writ of certiorari to the U.S. Court of Appeals for 4th Circuit and Motion to Advance 1969 (Box-folder 9:8)
  - Court Documents 1969 (Box-folder 9:9)
  - Enrollment Membership Information 1969 (Box-folder 9:10)
  - Boundary Lines Proposed Senior High School 1969-1970 (Box-folder 9:11)
  - Letters 1969-1971 (Box-folder 9:12)
  - Integration Resolutions 1969-1970 (Box-folder 9:13)
  - Court Memorandum 30 December 1969 (Box-folder 9:14)
  - Appeal US District Court, Raleigh, NC 1969 (Box-folder 9:15)
  - Pairing of Schools 3 February 1969 (Box-folder 9:16)
  - Correspondence Equal Education Opportunities, Washington & Charlottesville 1969 (Box-folder 9:17)
  - Beckett Case, Depositions 16 April 1969 (Box-folder 10:1)
  - Beckett Case, Depositions Volumes I, II 22-23 April, 1969 (Box-folder 10:2)
  - Beckett Case, Depositions Volumes VII, VIII, X 29 April, 7 May, 9 May 1969 (Box-folder 10:3)
  - Beckett Case, Depositions Volumes III and others 1969 September (Box-folder 11:1)
  - Beckett Case, Depositions Volumes III & V 1969 October (Box-folder 11:2)
  - Beckett Case, Trial Proceedings Volume VII 1969 October (Box-folder 11:3)
  - Beckett Case, Deposition 5 October 1969 (Box-folder 11:4)
  - Beckett Case, Depositions, Volume II 9 October 1969 (Box-folder 12:1)
  - Beckett Case, Depositions, Volume IV 1969 October 11 (Box-folder 12:2)
  - Beckett Case, Depositions, Volume VI 1969 October 14 (Box-folder 12:3)
  - Beckett Case, Proceedings, Volume VIII 1969 October 16 (Box-folder 13:1)
  - Beckett Case, Proceedings, Volume IX 1969 October 17 (Box-folder 13:2)
  - Beckett Case, Volume XI 1969 November 11 (Box-folder 13:3)
  - Beckett Case, Volumes A-C 8 Dec 1969 (Box-folder 13:4)
  - Court Case, Carlotta Brewer 1969-1975 (Box-folder 14:1-2)
  - Desegregation Faculty 1969-1977 (Box-folder 14:3)
  - Desegregation Court Correspondence 1969-1972 (Box-folder 13:4)
  - Integration City Attorney 1969-1970 (Box-folder 13:5)
  - Integration Choice of School 1969-1970 (Box-folder 13:6)
  - Integration Attorney General 1969-1970 (Box-folder 14:7)
  - Integration Long Range Plan 1969-1970 (Box-folder 15:1)
  - Integration News Clippings 1969-1970 (Box-folder 15:2)
  - Objections from the Justice Department 1969-1970 (Box-folder 15:3)
  - Court Orders 1970s (Box-folder 15:4)
  - Briefs, Brewer Case (Box-folder 15:5)
  - Profiles of Change Trends since 1970 1970-1978 (Box-folder 15:6)
  - Guidelines for Faculty Balancing 1970 March 4 (Box-folder 15:7)
  - Memorandum 22 June 1970 (Box-folder 15:8)
  - Decision 4th Circuit Court 22 June 1970 (Box-folder 15:9)
  - District Court Order 23 June 1970 (Box-folder 15:10)
  - Statement of Vincent J. Thomas 14 July 1970 (Box-folder 15:11)
  - Statement of Vincent J. Thomas 27 July 1970 (Box-folder 15:12)
  - Authorization for Athletes 1969-1970 (Box-folder 15:13)
  - Administrative Transfers 1969-1970 (Box-folder 1969-1970)
  - Petition for Writ Supreme Court October Term, 1969 1969 (Box-folder 15:15)
  - Federal Enforcement of School Desegregation Report 1969 (Box-folder 15:16)
  - Racial Distribution of Administrators and Faculty 29 September 1969 (Box-folder 15:17)
  - Norview Coronado Elementary Schools 4 August 1969 (Box-folder 15:18)
  - Depositions Beckett Box 29 July 1970 and 27 August 1970 (Box-folder 15:19)
  - Court Order 29 July 1970 (Box-folder 15:20)
  - Depositions Beckett Case, Volume I 1970 August 11 (Box-folder 16:1)
  - Depositions Beckett Case, Volume I 1970 (Box-folder 16:2)
  - Court Order 27 August 1970 (Box-folder 16:3)
  - School Enrollment and Racial Distribution 16 September 1970 (Box-folder 16 September 1970)
  - Report of Student Membership 16 September 1970 (Box-folder 16:5)
  - Complaint against School Board, McDaniel 1970 October (Box-folder 16:6)
  - Transfer Papers 1970 (Box-folder 16:7)
  - Response to Questions Propounded 1970 (Box-folder 16:8)
  - NAACPs Motion for Further Relief 1970 (Box-folder 16:9)
  - Depositions Beckett Case 1970 (Box-folder 16:10)
  - Plan for Unitary Schools 1970-1971 (Box-folder 16:11)
  - Complaint US District Court 1970-1971 (Box-folder 16:12)
  - Revised Score Sheet 1970-1971 (Box-folder 16:13)
  - Number of Sections of Each Grade above First Floor 1970 (Box-folder 16:14)
  - Richmond Division 1970-1971 (Box-folder 16:15)
  - Miscellaneous 1970-1971 (Box-folder 17:1)
  - Swann et al 1971 (Box-folder 17:2)
  - Fees, Court Costs 1971 (Box-folder 17:3)
  - Brief, Brewer Case 1971 (Box-folder 17:4)
  - Richmond 1971 (Box-folder 17:5)
  - Selection & Training of Bus Drivers 1971 (Box-folder 17:6)
  - Concerned Citizens Motions & Objections 1971 (Box-folder 17:7)
  - Integration Statement by Chairman of the School Board 1971 (Box-folder 17:8)
  - Answer to the Motion for Further Relief 1971 (Box-folder 17:9)
  - Letters, Busing 1971 (Box-folder 17:10)
  - Supplemental Brief of NAACP 1971 June 1 (Box-folder 17:11)
  - 4th Circuit Court of Appeals 1971 June 10 (Box-folder 17:12)
  - Court Order 1971 July 19 (Box-folder 17:13)
  - Court Order 1971 Jul 28 (Box-folder 17:14)
  - Memorandum 1971 July 28 (Box-folder 17:15)
  - Court Order 1971 July 28 (Box-folder 17:16)
  - Motion to Vacate Stay by the NAACP 1971 August 25 (Box-folder 17:17)
  - Response of School Board in Opposition to Vacate Stay 1971 August 25 (Box-folder 17:18)
  - Motion to Vacate Stay & Motion for Rending Appeal 1971 August 25 (Box-folder 17:19)
  - Motion for Injunction Regarding Appeal 1971 August 31 (Box-folder 17:20)
  - Integration 1971-1972, Petitions from Parents regarding busing 1971-1972 (Box-folder 17:21)
  - Total Full-Time Professional & Instructional Staff 1971 October 2 (Box-folder 17:22)
  - Proposed Amendments to the Pupil Assignment Plan 1971-1972 (Box-folder 17:23)
  - Justice Department Opposition for Stay 1971 (Box-folder 17:24)
  - Membership & Racial Distribution 30 September 1971 (Box-folder 17:25)
  - Feeder Schools & Pattern 1971 September (Box-folder 17:26)
  - Whitmore Complaint 1971 September 28 (Box-folder 17:27)
  - Enrollment Data, September 30, 1969, 1970, 1971 1969-1971 (Box-folder 18:1)
  - Report to the Court 1971 October (Box-folder 18:2)
  - Summary of Enrollment Data 1971 October 11 (Box-folder 18:3)
  - Supreme Court 1971 October (Box-folder 18:4)
  - Complaints from Parents Concerning Bus Service 1971 (Box-folder 18:5)
  - Motion to Dispense with Printing Brewer/Allgood 1971 October (Box-folder 18:6)
  - Bus Fare Ordinance 1971 December 6 (Box-folder 18:7)
  - Senior High Schools with 100% Senior Options & 9th Graders Assigned 1971-1972 (Box-folder 18:8)
  - Court Complete Exhibit Sets 1971-1972 (Box-folder 18:9)
  - Exceptions to Norfolk Plan 1971-1972 (Box-folder 18:10)
  - Amendment to the Plan 1971-1972 (Box-folder 18:11)
  - Teachers Suit for Full Salary under Price Freeze 1971-1972 (Box-folder 18:12)
  - Busing/Miscellaneous Articles, reports, etc. 1971-1972 (Box-folder 18:13)
  - Racial Breakdown Involving Administrators 18:14 (Box-folder 18:14)
  - Score Sheet Proposed 1971-1972 (Box-folder 18:15)